Michael Coulterman

5602 Goddard Street | Manotick, Ontario | mscoulte@gmail.com | cell: (613)-325-9271

Summary of Qualifications

Computer Networking and Technical Support Professional, with excellent time management and organizational skills. Highly experienced in customer/client service and working in team-oriented environments, both working under others and in leadership roles. Adapts easily to change and is able to quickly and decisively analyze complex situations and provide solutions. Known for being independent, a strong communicator and able to formulate ideas in a clear and articulate manner.

Education & Training

B.A. Applied Economics -Honours | Carleton University

Graduated June 2015 | Ottawa, Ontario

Computer Network Technology | Herzing College

Graduated with Honours May 2017 | Ottawa, Ontario 2016/2017 CNT Award of Merit

Full Stack Flex – Web Development Boot Camp | Carleton University

Graduating August 2020 | Ottawa, Ontario

A+ Certification | COMPTIA

Certificate Awarder December 2017 | Ottawa, Ontario

Work Experience

MD Financial Management

April 2018 – January 2020 | Ottawa, Ontario

Technical Support Analyst

- 2nd Level Deskside Support specializing in Hardware/Technical issues-Troubleshooting/Investigating root cause.
- Managed and assisted with various IT related projects:
 - o Office 365 Upgrade
 - o Implementing secondary authentication RSA for Remote VPN users
 - o PC Refresh of entire organization (1500 Employees)
 - o iPhone Deployment for Client Facing Staff
 - E-mail/Office migration and decoupling from parent organization (CMA-Scotia) after company Sale
 - o In-House Service Desk Launch
- Handled day to day technical support service tickets, documenting detailed notes of all troubleshooting/steps followed in order to resolve technical issues.
- Developed and maintained an active knowledge base library in order to provide level 1 support with resources to quickly solve active or common issues.

• Maintained all head office meeting/board room technology including smartboards, projectors and Barco-Clickshare technology.

La Relance Technology Service (STLR)

May 2017 - April 2018 | Gatineau, Quebec

Network Support- Junior Admin | Sept 2017- May 2018

- Provided technical Support for the 3 divisions and parent company (La Relance)
- Managed company network (Wi-Fi, Ethernet, Firewall, Active Directory, WDS)
- Involved in Server migration project. Configuring new Windows Server 2012 and migrating existing data from previous Server's infrastructure. (Windows 2008)
- Basic configurations of Cisco routers and switches.
- Troubleshooting various office technologies (Projectors, Smart Boards, Printers, Routers)
- Interacted with users in person and over e-mail to provide support for IT technical issues.

Computer Technician (Team Lead) | May 2017-September 2017

- Troubleshoot used computers & hardware
- · Managed team to ensure orders were fulfilled to a certain level of quality
- Refurbished computers for future educational use
- Organized Equipment database & Computer Orders
- Supervised & assisted with students and volunteers

Bartender (Part Time) | Manotick Curling Club

Oct 2016 - Apr 2018 | Ottawa, Ontario

- Managed Bar stock/inventory
- Assisted in rink maintenance and organizing of special events

Teaching Assistant (Part Time) | DEFT Learning Academy

Nov 2015 – Apr 2016 | Ottawa, Ontario

- Assisted in the tutoring of grade school students in Mathematics
- Marked/ Graded assignments and class work

Splash Pools & Spas Inc

May 2013 - Oct 2015 | Ottawa, Ontario

Service Management (Seasonal Part Time)

- Scheduled a variety of service appointments throughout the city in an efficient manner.
- Provided assistance and expertise to customers and clients about various equipment diagnostics as well as proper procedures to follow.

Shipping & Receiving (Seasonal Full Time)

- Coordinated with project managers to order the proper/necessary equipment for a pool/spa installation based on the customers purchase.
- Responsible for ordering specialty items/ parts not carried in stock for customers in need of
 parts for a specific brand of equipment and handling customer warranties.
- Made weekly/bi-weekly orders of chemicals, equipment and parts in order to maintain an
 acceptable level of stock in the store.

- Managed the retail clerks and assisted them with any knowledge or customer based issues.
- Received all incoming deliveries and ensured the merchandise delivered matched with what was ordered

Technical Skills:

- Proficient in Windows XP/7/10 as well as Windows Server 2008/2012
- Proficient in all aspects of Windows Office including Outlook, Word, Power Point and Excel
- Basic Intermediate skills dealing with Cisco Routers and Switches.
- Experienced with Troubleshooting many Financial Applications including Sage 50, ACT, RPM technologies, Bloomberg
- Experienced in setting up Network equipment such as Servers, Firewalls, Switches, Wireless Routers, etc.

Continuing education

- Currently in enrolled in a Full Stack Flex Web Development Program
- Competent in HTML, CSS, JS.